good evening ladies and gentlemen a very
warm welcome to ICICI Lumbard General
Insurance company limited's Q4 FY 2024
and fy2 24 earnings conference
call from the Senior Management we have
with us today Mr sanjie mantri MD and
CEO of the company Mr gopal balachandran
CFO Mr alok Agarwal executive
director Mr Girish nyak chief technology
and health underwriting and
claims Mr sandip gadia Chief corporate
solutions group and Mr Anand singi the
chief retail and government
business please note that any statements
or comments made in today's call that
may look like forward-looking statements
are based on information presently
available to the management and do not
constitute an indication of any future
performance as the future involves risks
and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being
expressed as a reminder all participant
lines will be in the listen only mode
there will be an opportunity for you to
ask questions after the presentation
concludes should you need assistance
during this conference please signal an
operator by pressing star and then zero
on your touchone phone
I now hand the conference over to Mr
sanjie mantri MD and CEO ICI Lombard
General Insurance Limited thank you and
over to you sir thank
you good evening to each one of you
thank you for joining the earning
conference call of icsa lombar limited
for quarter 4 and financial year
2024 let me give you a brief overview of
the industry Trends and developments
that we have witnessed in the past few
months post this our CFO Mr gopal bandan
will share the financial performance of
the company for the quarter and the year
ended March 31st
2024 during the quarter Len economy
continued its robust growth trajectory
with key high frequency indicators
reflecting healthy economic conditions
for the financial year 2024 India's GDP
growth is expected to be
7.6% looking ahead a normal Southwest
Monsoon should support agriculture
activity boost rural demand and help
overall
sentiments however any worsening of
geopolitical tensions or a global
slowdown may have an adverse
impacts now talking about Auto industry
Private Car Sales witnessed Rob robust
growth for the financial year 2024 aided
by improved supplies and sustained
customer demand as per CM data over 4.2
million Vehicles were sold in the year
the industry also sh saw a shift in the
customer preference from entry level
cars to SUV thus contribution of SUV in
private car segment has gone up from 37%
to 49% in last two
years as mentioned in the earn last
earning calls uptick in ruler demand saw
two wheer sales grow by
25% in Q4 to touch 4.5 million the
annual two- wheeler sales also surpassed
the financial year 2020 figure and stood
at 18 million Vehicles during the year
around 1.7 million commercial VRE were
sold which was D driven primarily by
good Traction in infra and other core
sectors health insurance continued to be
the largest product segment for the
industry as per data published in the I
annual report for financial year 2023
the growth in number of lives have been
primally driven by the group health
business and we expect this trend to
continue for financial year 2024 as well
the commercial line of business witness
growth supported by strong government
capital expenditure related to
infrastructure development consequently
engineering lines of business witness a
robust growth during the
year we remain optimistic that the
industry will continue to grow given the
favorable macros regulatory changes low
penetration and relatively positive
consumer
sentiments coming to Performance The
General insurance industry delivered a
year- onye gross direct premium income
growth of 12.8% for financial year 2024
excluding crop and Mass health the
growth stood at
14.8% overall the combined ratio for the
industry was at 11 12.2% for 9 month
Financial year 2024 as against 11 16.2%
for 9 month Financial year
2023 for motor the combin ratio was at
11 18.2% for 9 month Financial year 2024
and against
121.9 for 9 month Financial year
2023 in our last earning calls we had
mentioned Improvement in the industry
combin ratio for motor for H1 Financial
year 2024 by fin by 400 basis points to
19.4% from
123.5 for hm Financial year 2023 there
has been a further Improvement of 3
basis points for quarter three only in
the combined ratio for motor at 11 15.9%
as against 11 18.9% during the same
period last year the motor combined
ratio for private players in Q3
Financial year 2024 was at 110.71202012
this in coming days now I would like to
touch upon certain regulatory
announcements on March 20th 2024 after
comprehensive review of regulatory
framework The Authority notified a
number of principal based prescriptions
the new regulations include Den
notification of all tariff notified by
the Earth tariff advisory committee
which continued to be enforced December
2006 with the den notification of the
existing tariffs the company is at the
Liberty to design all the general
insurance products in line with its own
underwriting policy this would
facilitate insurers to respond faster to
the Emerging Market requirements and to
design Innovative products to cater to
customers needs it may be mentioned that
the pricing of motor TP line of business
continues to be under the Tariff
regime rural social sector and motor
third party obligation prescribes a
minimum insurance business to be
undertaken by the insurers the
compliance and measurement of these
statut obligations has been revised in
order to enhance the insurance
penetration Vima sugam Insurance
electronic Marketplace regulations allow
for establishment of a digital public
infrastructure Insurance electronic
marketplace with this The Authority has
set out a vision of democratizing
insurance to achieve the goal of
insurance for all by
2047 we believe the regulatory
developments are favorable for the
industry I would like to further
reiterate that the company we will as a
company we will continue to leverage the
benefits of being a diversified
multi-product and multi-distribution
organization as we capitalize on the
existing and emerging business
opportunities in the
sector now I will speak about the
business impact for us in quarter 4 and
financial year
2024 the company grew by 22% during
quarter 4 Financial year 2024 excl
including a oneoff transaction in the
motor segment last year growth was 15.8%
which was higher than the industry
growth of
99.5% for
99.5% for financial year 2024 the
company grew Away by 17.8% as again the
industry growth of
12.8% excluding the one of transaction
last year growth for financial year 2024
was
16.4% let me now touch upon our
performance in key business segments
during the and financial year 2024 in
the commercial business segment we
continue to consolidate our Market
position by leveraging our unique
distribution Network enhanced by value
added Services student risk based
underwriting and highly rated reinsurer
Capac
capacities during quarter 4 2024 we viw
at 11.3% as against an industry growth
of
11% for financial year 2024 we grew at
14.7% which was higher than the industry
growth of 10
% further during the year we acude
market shares across segments such as
fire Marine cargo engineering and
liability as we speak we are at an
industry leading position in Marine
cargo and liability line of business
while being the second largest in Fire
and Engineering line of
business last year we experienced
significant rate hardening in the
reinsurance terms in line with global
Trends however as anticipated the recent
April renewals have largely been
benign motor continues to be the largest
contributor to our product mix over the
year we have developed strong
capabilities across distribution
underwriting claims servicing and actal
practices given our presence across all
three Subs segments of Private Car two
wheeler and CV we would continue to
balance our portfolio mixed depending on
the market opportunities as we saw some
discipline return to the market we
scaled up our position in a calibrated
manner and consequently ended the year
as an industry
leader the growth for us during the
quarter was
27.3% excluding the oneoff transaction
last year the growth for quarter 4 2024
was 13.4% as against the industry growth
of
99.6% for financial year 2024 we grew at
12.3% excluding the one of transaction
last year the annual growth was 8.9%
against the industry growth of 12.9%
the growth in motor segment was AED by
strong growth in new Private Car segment
which grew at 23% for quarter for
2024 and 28% for financial year 2024
which was higher than CM volume growth
of 12% and 8.4% respectively a new two
wheer growth was 11% for quarter 4 and
133% for financial year
2024 while the CM volume growth was
24.9% and 12.3%
respectively as real demand picks up we
expect to see the trend continue for two
wheelers in the new CV segment we degw
by 2.1% in quarter 4 2024 and 1.9% in
financial year 2024 while the CM volume
growth was .1% and 14.4%
respectively for financial year 2024 our
mix of Private Car two-wheeler and
Commercial Vehicle stands at 51.4% 26
.8% and 21.9%
respectively we also continue to build
efficiency in motor claims in quarter 4
2024 we were able to service 70% of our
agency and direct claims through
preferred partner Network up from 54% in
quarter for
2023 for the next year we expect mid
single digit growth in Private Car Sales
while the two wheer segment is expected
to deliver 8 to 10% growth CV sales are
expected to grow in double digits in
line with the previous year on account
of demand from infras sector the health
the health segment continued to be the
fastest growing segment for the industry
we grew faster than the industry both in
quarter 4 and financial year 2024
registering a growth of 29% for the
quarter and full
year the group health employer employee
segment we grew at 31.7% in quarter 4
2024 and 30.3% in financial year 2024
the change in the underlying industry
pricing sentiments resulted in customers
moving towards insurers with Superior
servicing
capabilities our retail Health business
grew by 21.8% in quarter 4 2024 against
the industry growth of
19.9% for financial year 2024 our retail
growth view retail business view at 20%
as against and the industry growth at
19.1% we would continue to invest in
this segment in terms of human
technology ol human human capital
technology and knowledge Capital to
further improve our market share our
current
retail agency manager count stands at600
we will continue to strengthen our
growth level as we expect to achieve far
more than far more in this
segment our bank insurance and key
relationship grew at 16.7% for the
quarter and 20.2% for the financial year
2024 within this ICA group distribution
view by 39 99.4% for quarter 4 Financial
year 2024 and 22.5% for financial year
2024 we will continue to deep mine our
existing Relationships by creating new
value streams and at the same time focus
on acquiring new relationship during the
year we added over 80 Banker
Partnerships in our last call we spoke
about a vision of one is one team under
this one of our initiative that we have
outlined in our one ey is our one one
digital strategy through this we aim to
consolidate our customer facing digital
assets of I take care website and
alliances along with our distribution
facing front ends this will allow us to
exploit the synergies across all our
platforms which will result in benefits
to the
company our onetop solution for all
insurance and wellness needs the IL take
care app has surpassed 9.3 million user
downloads till date we continue our
growth momentum with 8 million user
downloads for the quarter in the same
period we sour premium over 1.13 billion
and a premium of 3.68 billion for
financial year 2024 registering a 3X
increase on a YY
basis our overall customer facing
digital business grew at 29.5% in
quarter 4 and 39% in financial year 2024
and constitute 6.8% and 6% respectively
of our overall business
last week we announced a strategic tie
up with policy Bazar our tie up is aimed
at Levering leveraging the strength of
the two institutions to create a
superior customer value
proposition after transitioning to Cloud
we have continued to make significant
Investments on modernization of our
technology
platforms along with this our Core
Business and Technology transformation
project project Oran is also underway
project tan would entail three pivotal
pillars of reimagining processes with a
digital first approach modernizing
technology by shifting away from Legacy
systems and enhancing stakeholder
experience to Superior en engagement
models we are excited to share that we
have kickstarted the transformation
Journey with some of our preferred line
of businesses and are witnessing the
initiatives shaping up nicely we firmly
believe project to land will be a key
enabler on a vision of one Isle one
team as the EMP on the new Financial
Year we will focus on leveraging our
multi-product multi-distribution
strategy through effective use of data
digital advancements and launching new
products will maintain focus on scaling
up for profit pools while contining to
grow as one Al one team now I would
request gopal to take you through the
financial numbers for the year for the
Recently concluded quarter and the year
thanks aie and uh good evening to each
one of you I will now give you a brief
overview of the financial performance of
the recently concluded quarter and
financial years we have uploaded the
results presentation on our website you
can access it as we walk you through the
performance numbers during the quarter
icca Bank acquired additional Equity
shares of the company consequently the
shareholding of the bank in the company
has increased to more than 50% and the
company has become a subsidiary of the
bank gross direct premium income of the
company was at R 2 47.7 6 billion in f24
as against
210.25 billion in fi23 a growth of
17.8% which was higher than the industry
growth of
12.8% excluding crop and Mass health the
gdpi growth of the company was at
17.1% which was higher than the industry
growth of 14.8% in
f24 GDP of the company was at rupes
60.73 billion in quarter 4 fi 24 as
against rupes 49.77 billion in quarter 4
fi23 a growth of
22% this growth was higher than the
industry growth of
99.5% excluding crop and Mass health
gdpi growth was at 22% which was again
higher than the industry growth of 13.8%
in quarter 4 fi 24 our gdpi growth
during fi 24 was primarily driven by
growth in the preferred segments the
overall gdpi growth of our Property and
Casualty segment grew by 14.7% at rupes
68.5 1 billion in FY 24 as against R
59.73 billion in fi23 on the retail side
of the business GDP of the motor segment
was at rupees
96.34% the advanc premium was at rupes
33.3 billion at March 31 2024 as
againsted R 33.4 billion as at December
31 2023 GDP of the health segment was at
R 61.71 billion in f24 as against rupes
47.825445
our agents which included the point of
sale distribution count was at 128 411
as on March 31224 up from
12588 as on December 31 2023 during the
year we witnessed catastrophic events
namely Cyclone Vier jooy North Indian
floods and Cyclone Mong resultantly
combined ratio was 103.3 for the fer fi
24 as against 10 14.5% for
fi23 excluding the impact of the cat
losses of rupees 1.37 billion for the
full year the combin ratio would have
been at 1 10
12.5% for the quarter combin ratio was
10 12.2% in quarter 4 fi 24 as against
10 14.2% in quarter 4 of f23 our
investment assets Rose to rupes 48907
billion as at March 31 2024 up from
rupes 48.67 billion as at December 31
2023 our investment leverage net of
borrowings was 4.09 times as at March 31
2024 as against 4.11 times as at
December 31 2023 investment income was
Ates
35.262781
this year as against rupes 8.17 billion
in Q4 of last year our capital gains net
of impairment of investment assets St at
R 5.51 billion in fi 24 as compared to R
4.53 billion in
fi23 capital gains net of empowerment of
investment assets stood at rupes 1.56
billion in quarter 4 fi 24 as compared
to rupes 1.59 billion in quarter 4 fi23
our profit before tax grew by 21% Ates
2.55 billion in f24 as against R 21.13
billion in fi23 whereas profit before
tax grew by 21.9% at R 6.98 billion in
Q4 fi 24 as against 5.73 billion in Q4
fi23 consequently profit after tax grew
by 11% at rupes 19.19 billion in f24 as
against rupes
17.29% in fi 24 profit after tax grew by
18.9% Ates 5.2 billion in Q4 fi2 4 from
rupes 4.37 billion in Q4
fi23 the board of directors has proposed
a final dividend of rupes 6 per share
for f524 this payment is however subject
to approval of shareholders in the uing
annual gender meeting of the company the
overall dividend for fi 24 including the
proposed final dividend is rupes 11 per
share last year the overall dividend was
rupes 10 per share return on average
Equity was 17.2% in fi 24 as against
17.7% in fi23
return on average equity for the quarter
4 FY 24 was 17.8% as against 17.2% in
quarter 4
fi23 solvency ratio was at 2.62 times at
March 31 2024 as against 2.57 times as
at December 31 2023 continued to be
higher than the minimum regulatory
requirement of 1.5 times as I conclude I
would like to reiterate that we continue
to stay focused on driving profitable
growth sustainable value creation and
safeguarding interest of policy holders
at all times we would uh we would like
to thank you all for attending this
earnings call and we'll be happy to take
any questions uh at this point Thank
you thank you very much we will now
begin the question and answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and one on their touchone
telephone if you wish to withdraw
yourself from the question queue you may
press star and
two participants are requested to please
use handsets while asking a question
ladies and Gent gentlemen we will now
wait for a moment while the question Q
assembles the first question comes from
the line of Shrea Shivani from clsa
please go
ahead thank you and um congratulations
on a good set of numbers I have three
questions uh so first is on the overall
growth Outlook so a health book for us
has done quite well since past 2 years
since fi 22 the growth has been north of
25 30 40% right uh so
so um expecting some moderation and
growth going ahead what will be the key
drivers for growth in fi
2526 uh which segments would be driving
majority of the growth and how much
higher than industry growth can we
deliver in the years to come given that
motor segment is still the the combine
ratio is still though there has been an
improvement and discipline has come in
but it's still quite a high combined
ratio for us to for one to expect us to
grow very fast in the motor segment so
that's my first question on key growth
drivers and how much faster than
industry can we grow in fi 2526 uh
second is on the motor TP segment uh
looking at the reserve triangles
reserving triangles for the motor
segment PP segment specifically so there
has been a much higher Reserve release
in accident year 18 1920 I mean the
trend looks much better than the
previous prior year Trend so how should
we read this data does this also
significantly add to your fi 24 loss
ratio Improvement on YY basis uh apart
from more new cars being sold um so
that's that's my second question and Sir
on the third question is on the combined
ratio we've done quite well on the
combined ratio side um already at 100
for the fourth quarter that has G gone
by much better uh numbers over there so
um going ahead what is our guidance on
combined ratio and one question that i'
also asked at the anist meet about uh
considering uh natural calamities as
business as usual going ahead does that
change our combined ratio guidance in
anyway these are my three questions
thank
you so I just let goal take the other
one and I'll tell you what is our view
yeah so I think uh if you look at uh on
the first one sh I think uh if you look
at it from an overall Market perspective
uh I think as we have always been saying
we have been we have always been looking
at this business in the context of being
a multi-product multi distribution setup
and therefore to that extent different
segment of businesses uh presents
opportunities for growth maybe at
different points of time and hence to
that extent is where I think we have
been able to kind of put in place a
model in place by which we are able to
leverage the growth potential uh so and
it is in that context when you look at
the overall year gone by I think we have
been able to have an outperformance
relative to the market growth and if you
look at in terms of how we are heading
into the next year I think there's a lot
of positive momentum that we see from
from an overall Market perspective as
well one of course this slew of uh
regulatory reforms that we spoke as a
part of the introductory uh remarks I
think that aers well both from a market
standpoint and even from the opportunity
that it gives for is Lombard I think is
very very positive second I think if you
look at the thrust that the government
is putting on in terms of in general
looking at significant thrust of
infrastructure development that
obviously presents a lot more
opportunities on multiple segments of
businesses whether you look at it in the
commercial line space uh maybe for
example uh thrust on engineering
projects to begin with obviously to that
extent it kind of AIDS in logistics uh
transportation to again look at uh
growth profitably and more importantly
it is also expected to lead to let's say
higher number of uh jobs and therefore
to that extent it like as I said kind of
augur very well uh in terms of the
opportunity that one sees specific to
your point on health I think as we have
always said even in the past I think uh
the kind of opportunity that one sees in
the market if you look at few years back
the market was significantly stressed in
terms of the loss experience or and more
importantly whether you look at it from
a combined isue standpoint given that
some of the players are already kind of
looking at uh reversing some element of
pricing within Group Health and
particularly on the employer employee
side it obviously kind of augers well
and that's the reason why you see us uh
continuing to grow disproportionately
relative to the market and even as we
head into
fi25 We Believe health for for the
industry as well will continue to be by
far the one of the fastest growing
segments and within that even for ICU
Lombard we see an opportunity on health
both in the groups Health as well as on
the retail Health segments uh so that's
whe whether the growth will be
continuing to be at 25 will it slightly
get moderated I think we will obviously
wait for things to evolve but honestly
as we have said even in the past I don't
think uh from a market perspective we
will continue to see prolonged periods
of 25 to 30% growth from an industry
standpoint so I think that's something
that we will obviously watch for the
second question on yours in terms of the
motor third party reserving triangle I
think uh it's good that the market is
starting to look at the triangle
disclosures uh from an overall Market
perspective I think that again augers
well because then every company is being
kind of proed to appropriate uh level of
scrutiny from a market perspective and
hence to that extent it again uh augers
well from our overall Market discipline
uh in terms of uh uh the some of the
let's say the releases that you spoke
about I think if you ask us the way I
would kind of respond to it is whether
have we is there any change in the
approach of our reserving philosophy the
approach is not changed and in line with
what we have been seing even in in the
earlier quarters I think the way to look
at on the third party book as you
rightly mentioned is more more on an
annual basis and in fact if you
recollect uh even last time in the
quarters earnings call we did speak
about a range within which we see the
loss experience play out for motor as a
category and just to kind of refresh
that we had said motor own damage loss
experience is something that we see in
the range of 60 to 65% and motor third
party as a segment we had said we would
be kind of operating at a range between
65 to 70% and both of that Blended is
where we had said motor as a category
would run in that range of 64 65% and if
you look at the full year numbers both
on motor own damage as well as on motor
third party I think broadly the outcome
of the book that we have been able to
underwrite has been within that range
that I just kind of uh refreshed having
said that one of the key deliverables
that we would obviously watch for which
also put which we put as a part of the
uh introductory remarks is on motor
third party pricing now as she speak
statement of fact is we have not seen a
price change uh so we will watch for
development in that space and therefore
to that extent the risk selection will
continue to be driven by some of the
factors that we see as we speak in terms
of no price increase thus far so H we
will be guided more by that in terms of
how we see the opportunity the range of
loss experiences is a function of what I
kind of mentioned your last point on
combined
ratio I think uh shares clearly I mean
the qu four numbers on the combin ratio
which read that
102.2 and there about where does it play
the overall commentary in terms of what
we have spoken tail WIS available
sectoral reform which are being
initiated by the
regulator uh we see a play and we do see
that we can have a you know overall 50
basis Improvement further to what we had
said we will achieve as a team by
quarter four of next year U but uh again
we will keep revisiting and absolutely
we'll keep communicating but we do see
shoots and we that kind of an
improvement can come in overall for us
as an
entity so so what you're saying
basically by fi25 we were targeting 102
that can be uh 50 books uh lower at
101.5 unless there is some other and
what about the catastrophe events are we
are we still watching it or have we come
to a conclusion on how we should be
dealing with so clearly I think gopal
also in the past has been mentioning
that the frequency of catastroph event
on the annual basis uh has got increased
and do we factor that when we speak
about it yes there is a level of
factoring but like a last year was an
exceptional one which was more than the
factoring and that's why we keep stating
in terms of what would have happened if
those Cat event would not have been in
terms of quantum to that extent uh see
in the business of writing risk at a
fundamental level do we watch do we
Factor all of that is part of the
process but the extend the EXT to the
event is something which we all await uh
we will keep you updated on that part
but there's some elements which
obviously is Big de when we see that uh
we are overall expecting an improvement
of 50 basis
points okay sir so thank thank you this
is useful thank you thank
you ladies and gentlemen we request you
to please restrict your questions to two
questions per
participant we have the next question
from the line of sanet Goda from avendus
Spark please go ahead uh yeah uh thank
you thank you for the opportunity I I
have two key questions uh one one
question is with the with respect to the
regulation um just just my my
understanding of that new obligation
Norms on motor TP seems to be more
stringent than it was in the previous
regime so so just wanted to understand
whether whether we would be confident to
fulfill the obligation of motor TP in
the new Norms uh is is the point we
wanted to I mean just wanted to
understand and and how you will achieve
it that's that's one question and and
second strategic question which I want
to understand is that you you have
highlighted about one L um but but if
you want to quantify the number uh due
to one L what are the synergies you are
expecting to see either in the form of
gwp growth because because you're now
aligning agents across the business
segment or distribution across the
segments so so so you expect a synergies
and and if means quantify the number in
terms of gwp additional gwp or or maybe
be an additional Improvement in the
expense ratio because of these synergies
and and lastly on datae keeping uh uh if
you can share retail and Group Health
loss ratio and and gopal to last Point
sorry that that if if the no PP price
hike doesn't come are you still
confident that 65 to 70 motor off isue
is achievable or
not okay so I'll take the first two and
then the other one other the data that
you seeking in the last question gopal
will come in and give to you uh in terms
of the new TP regulations that have come
in see I mean the insurance The
Authority has clearly said that they're
looking for insurance for all by 2047
and for that some initiation has to be
done uh the contus of how this will uh
emerg for all of us has still to emerge
uh it's kind of work in progress but
that being said see we are multi-line
multi- product well distributed
franchise is so much of retail I mean
the am of we do
as an entity humongus so we are present
we would definitely back ourselves to
achieve uh uh the objectives that are
set by the regulator but we will be
speculating beyond the point as to where
we where we will be placed that we have
complete Clarity in terms of what's
expected from us so that's Point number
one under one one uh one team that we've
been talking about and really
emphasizing uh quantification
fundamentally comes with the quarter
results that you will see just
announcing and we would uh refrain from
attaching uh you know finite value
because the overall performance is
subject to scrutiny which we keep
announcing to all of you and uh uh are
we excited in terms of seeing both Top
Line and cost getting you know controll
in a relatively better manner the answer
is yes definitely and we do believe
coming quarters will ACR uh but we will
not be you know culling it out and
calling that this has happened because
of this overall the efficiency of the
company will be you know will be
reflected in how we perform as an entity
and there are multiple other aspects
that come you know we may have some
genuine savings we may choose to
reinvest also that so we would not like
to you know D on this on those
aspects but sanj you give away 50 basis
point better guidance than than what it
was last year so so is it because of
this oneel what you are trying
to again what what I would again you
know you know rush into I get from where
your excitement is coming from this
would be one of the control we always
maintained that the industry sentiments
also has to move in the positive
direction we have always maintain the
fact that we would be an output of where
the overall industry growth is and how
our own placement is so uh is this an
element that comes in and binds us
together as an organization 110% answer
is yes
uh but to quantify this this from this
output this mat has come because of one
one team will not
be will not be fair is all I'm saying so
there are multiple things that go in
that for the other two questions that
you had I'll ask gopal to rever to you
yeah so so sank on the health loss
numbers uh again I'll give you Q4
numbers first and then I'll will give
you the F your numbers Q4 on the uh ghi
which is employer employee segment this
is for four of last year which is fi23
that number is at
93.2% that number for quarter 4 of this
year is at
88.1% uh and on a full year basis for
the same segment I think the range that
we have spoken about is to operate in
the range of 94 95% if you look at fi23
the overall loss ratio on the ghi side
was
95.2% and this year we are at about
93.7% on retail Health again just to
kind of refresh uh what we have talked
about even in the past several quarters
is we're comfortable operating in the
loss ratio range which is between 65 to
70% in that context when you look at the
quarter 4 fi23 numbers retail which is
on the indemnity side that loss ratio
was about
61% that number for quarter four of this
year is at
64.6% and on a full year basis last year
number was
64.1 and the current year number is at
about
65.4 uh so that's in in response to your
second point on the health loss numbers
the last question of yours in in terms
of uh whether the range that I spoke
about of 65 to 70% in the context of
motor third party uh so again I think
that's the range that we have kind of
largely operated at I think the only
factor that I would say is uh in line
with again what we've been speaking even
in the past few quarters as in to say
that what we are seeing on ground is
also maybe an increased preference of
the courts to start giving compensation
in favor of uh the victims of the
insured and therefore so that's a trend
that we will obviously observe uh the
other factor which would again uh which
we have which we have again spoken of
which should be directionally positive
is also this whole six months law of
limitation in terms of how that gets
played out uh last year of course we did
see some developments and finally as we
have been saying the matter is presently
at the Supreme Court once the verdict
comes out I think we will again have to
see in terms of how that play gets
played out on ground so hence there are
again balancing forces in terms of ones
that could possibly see or reflect an
increase in the loss experience that's
purely then it's up to us in terms of
what kind of risk selection do we do and
the second is more a positive benefit at
least for IC Lombard from an over
overall Ro activeness standpoint and end
to that exent that that should kind of
Aid Us in terms of maintaining the loss
is show range of 65 to 70% so there are
lot of moving parts now at this point of
time I think we would want to kind of
stick with uh the 65 to 70% range and of
course we will see some of these factors
in terms of how that get paid out
through the
year uh perfect thanks thanks for your
responses thank you thanks than thank
you thank
you the next question is from the line
of nides from investtech please go
ahead uh thanks for the opportunity uh
first question is on IFRS so any uh any
update what are the timelines for
expected implementation of IFRS and what
impact on ourn and balance sheet
of so NES I think again in line with
what I had mentioned even in the last
earnings call I think we had said that
uh we are pretty much uh progressing
well in terms of doing the impact
assessment making sure that we get
ourselves uh ready for the
implementation which is effective from
fi 2526 Financial year uh and even last
quarter we did say that we will come
back in maybe a couple of quarters time
frame so honestly internally while we
are doing all of those and also watching
for uh the developments in terms of all
the necessary guidelines and standards
getting issued in the context of the
IFRS transition so therefore at this
point of time too early to call out but
as I always maintained I think we have
clearly spoken about three or four key
uh areas or aspects which is where we
would likely to see the impact of
transition play out in the context of
ifls so that doesn't change um whether
it is in terms of acquisition cost
whether it is in terms of discounting of
reserves whether it is in terms of Mark
to Market on the investment book and
maybe for few set of companies which
have kind of issued uh let's say stock
units or stock options so there will be
an element of uh cost through the
earnings so those are three or four key
areas where one would see an impact of
the transition play out specifically to
call out I think we will come back and
obviously keep all of you updated in
terms of uh where we are on the IFR
establish
sure sure and uh secondly in terms of
solvency ratio we are operating at
significantly higher number versus the
threshold uh and our Roes have also now
improved to 17 to 18% uh so do you think
of better utilization of capital going
forward no of course that's obviously
something that we kind of uh uh is
something that we always look for uh I
think one of the factors that you see
which also led to let's say Improvement
in solvency and of Improvement in
earnings over the last few years has
been our approach to as what sanjie has
also been talking about is to sustain
profitable growth as a theme and hence
in let's say relative to the market I
think we have been slightly slowing
going slow on some of the segments and
therefore to that extent we have not
been able to completely utilize the
solvency Capital what we are seeing is
what we kind of put out as a part of the
introductory remark which is to say that
on ground we are seeing semblance coming
back in uh some of the segments where we
have we have been a bit cautious and
therefore to that extent as we see let's
say incremental growth play out in line
in line with our approach to continue to
grow as well as kind of remain
profitable obviously there will be
consumption of capital that one would
see uh in terms of uh the way forward uh
and secondly I think the approach of the
philosophy that isos has always worked
with is to be slightly more prudent in
terms of the level of solvency that we
want to maintain given the fact that
Indian market still continues to operate
on a solvency one regime while again uh
thanks to the regulator they have been
significantly working on getting the
market again transition to a risk-based
capital regime obviously we will get to
know more in terms of the firm date of
implementation in terms of the
transition uh so hence that's that
that's something again that we will see
in terms of how does that result into in
so far as the consumption of capital is
concerned so while we do see growth
opportunities and hence to thatt we
believe we will continue to use the
capital uh
judiciously so and just lastly on the
provision for diation in value of
investment of around 68 crores what is
the reason for that and when we disclose
the capital gain number that is
excluding this rejoin the queue for
follow-up
questions okay sir all right thank
you the next question is from the line
of PR Jen from moil oswal please go
ahead uh yeah hi good evening uh so
firstly just a clarification when you
say 101.5 as a guidance that is for the
exit rate of Q4 of next year or it's for
the uh full year uh secondly if I you
know like just uh just going back to one
of the uh previous questions on the
motor TP business on your you know the
obligation if the share of CV goes up do
you still uh believe that that you know
65 to 70% guidance can be maintained um
and within that you know goal time and
again you know we've seen Q4 loss ratios
improve sequentially increase
sequentially for motor TP is it just
because of the adverse judgments that
come in Q4 or what is it that really
gives that kind of a loss ratio uptrend
in every fourth quarter uh yeah I think
those would be my two questions yeah
yeah maybe I'll take the the uh uh PP
loss isue part first uh I think Whenever
there is let's say
possible uh reduction in the TP loss
ises the questions gets asked the other
way around so and therefore to that
extent uh I think as I think I have
always kind of maintained that this is a
book which is much more longtail in
terms of loss development and therefore
to that extent given the nature of the
business you will always see cyclicality
SL fluctuations in the loss experience
of the book in in terms of its outcome
so therefore which is why I keep harping
on looking at the numbers ideally over
longer term but definitely not between
quarters look at it more on an annual
basis um and as I keep saying again
there are various factors that
influences uh let's say the loss
experience of the book I think uh so
hence to that extent you will get to see
fluctuations in the pp loss ratios
across Quarters on a full year basis is
what I spoke about in terms of trying to
maintain us operating at a segment uh I
mean segment loss ratio in that range of
65 to 70% now coming back to your first
second part of the question in terms of
link to motor third party is the
obligation now obviously the the
obligation is something that is
applicable to Industry at large and
therefore as as a company I mean uh we
have to make sure that we kind of meet
those uh obligations and I'm sure we
will have in place a plan by virtue of
which we are able to meet uh the
regulatory expectations I think the the
thought process in terms of the
regulator is coming out with the need to
bring about this change is again very
very positive because the whole thought
process is to try and make sure that the
industry kind of comes under the Ambit
of insurance and to that extent that's
very very positive and if you're able to
do as as an industry if you're able to
work collectively and maybe bring the
larger set of let's say uninsured
vehicles within the Ambit of insurance
that to my mind is a great positive and
hence to that extent uh I think we would
obviously work and make sure that we
able to meet those uh obligations of the
third party side uh the first part on
the combined ratio uh uh part I think
obviously yes I think dally the lens
that we have talked about mes is is uh
that we have we have been saying that
directionally the uh trajectory for us
is to bring down the combined over a
period of time and obviously this has to
be looked at in the context of how we
see the market environment operate at uh
which is why I think even as a part of
of the introductory remark we did point
out to say that the market is clearly
showing signs of at least from the
reported numbers on a 9month basis There
is almost a 400 basis point Improvement
in Combined uh from an overall Market
perspective and within that one of the
key segment which has been a larger
contributor of significant competitive
intensity has been motor now that's
again a segment which has again not just
on a half yearly basis even if you look
at the quarter quarter three numbers for
the market that's again shown an
improvement of almost about 300 basis
point so which is why I think we kind of
put out to say that there seems to be
some kind of a semblance coming back and
that's also getting reflected in terms
of the growth numbers that many of these
players were exhibiting in terms of
competitive aggression clearly you can
see a lot many players are starting to
kind of pull back so that gives us
possibly some kind of a confidence uh in
terms of how do we look at achieving
that uh combined objective that we laid
out and hence to that extent even in the
past I think what we have maintained is
what I mean if the market environment is
favorable there is no reason why we
would not be able to accelerate the
expectations of combine and that is
where we are that is why we stand and uh
and and in all finers we hope to kind of
achieve uh the thought process that we
laid out from a combined perspective
it's for it's for the full year right
that's the clarification I was so as
things stand and we'll be in touch on
this uh PR we believe the exit would be
overall with the 50 Bas less there are
serious plans of Investments also we
would uh Continue to update as the
quarters and fold because as gopal said
these are early signs that makes us
optimistic and sees the visibility of
this but uh there are multiple things
that will unfold as of now in our mind
it will be probably exit by quarter 4 is
where we would see this and if it gets
further accelerated we'll come back and
uh connect with you all by end of
quarter one of this year great thanks
and all the
best thank
you we have the next question from the
line of mukar ladda from noama wealth
please go ahead
uh hi congratulations on a good set of
numbers so most of my questions have
been answered I wanted to understand uh
investment yields have improved uh again
uh this quarter and even if we exclude
uh even if we exclude the capital gains
uh we're doing quite well so uh what is
the number that we should be sort of
looking at in this and uh what is the
duration how are we driving this
actually that's that is one question on
my end thank you sure M yeah so again
maduk I think again I would kind of
respond this in the context of I'm sure
you guys know it far better I think
obviously Investments have to be looked
at in terms of it return profile over a
period of time uh and hence to that
extent uh is how what we keep saying is
to look at Market opportunities in terms
of uh having a blended mix of the right
asset classes between both both fixed
income and equity and that's what we
have been kind of looking at over the
period of time in terms of realizing the
opportunities now specifically to Anor
point on what led to let's say the
increase in the uh interest yield or
let's say the overall return on the
portfolio is it is in line with the high
higher interest rate regime that we have
seen and obviously one leverages the
opportunity and even if you look at
historical past in terms of what kind of
a mix of our overall returns have been
in terms of Interest approvals to let's
say capital gains that mix is Broad been
on the interest acal side in the range
of 75 to 80% and on the capital gain
side a number that could range between
15 to 20 20 20 25% around that kind of a
threshold so hence to that extent is how
we see the opportunity playoff and
specifically if you look at our yield to
maturity uh on the fix income side the
yield to maturity currently stands at
about
7.4% uh so hence and that's the that's
the opportunity that one was able to
seize in the market and uh now can we
sustain this this obviously we will have
to wait and see how the interest rate
cycle play out uh there are here
expectations that you will start seeing
some kind of a rate reduction cycle play
through at some point of time again we
are positioned well even to capitalize
that opportunity but what could happen
at those points is our ability to
reinvest those uh realiz flows will
obviously get invested at a lower return
on the uh approval side but obviously we
are well positioned to capitalize the
opportunity from a capital gains
standpoint and therefore now to answer
your point on the overall range of
returns that we can operate with again
if you look at fi23 I think the overall
return on the realized book was roughly
at about
7.5% this number if you look at for fi
24 was roughly at about 7.98 closer to
8% um and the range I mean internally
the range that we kind of run with is to
kind of give a return profile between 7
to 7 and a half% and but over our last
now that we are almost 23rd 24th year of
operations I think the return profile
has been definitely better than that
particular range so that's the range
that we would be comfortable with and
hence that extent is where we would like
to operate
at thanks thanks your very helpful thank
you thanks for
the thank
you ladies and gentlemen we will now
take the last question for today from
the line of additi josi from JP Morgan
please go
ahead uh yes sir thank you for my
question taking my question uh just one
followup question uh um which I wanted
to uh understand from you on the compet
uh the investment intensity in the
channel uh so for the uh full year 2025
what is the Outlook as been of the
investment in the channel uh in terms of
the intensity are you going to increase
further or just wait for the Investments
the last in the last couple of years to
cify and then uh just some guidance on
that will be helpful so so again if you
look at I think what we put out it's a
part of the introductory comment is I
think just to kind of refresh again I
think we always looked ourselves as a
multi-distribution uh company and
therefore to that extent is how we see
opportunity play out across different
channels if you ask us would we stay
entrenched with each of these channels
the answer is a clear yes I think in so
far as let's say as we see new motor
vehicle sales gaining momentum and
therefore to that extent obviously we
will kind of Leverage on the access SL
Partnerships that we have been able to
create historically of working with OEM
slash more importantly the dealership
PCH points and that's the reason if you
look at across years the proportion of
dealership access that we have had out
of the total number of dealerships as a
country again just to kind of refresh
that number used to be between 50 to 55%
at the time when we did our listing
currently we have been able to reach
that number closer to in slightly
upwards of 65% uh in terms of the total
number of dealership so that will
continue to be an important channel of
distribution agency which kind of
encompasses between motor Health has
always been an area of opportunity and
that's a segment which obviously we have
been kind of expanding a lot more and
clearly we have seen benefits of the
Investments play out whether you look at
onme I think the growth rates over the
last several years have been very
positive even on let's say I would say
uh agency motor I think that's a segment
where we have talked about trying to
create a balanced mix between dealership
agency and let's say our direct
distribution so hence to that obviously
we will continue to leverage on uh
motage agency specifically and in
specific since we're talking in the
contu of agency retail health is always
a positive opportunity that one sees uh
and that's the reason why we put out
that number of the head count that we
have on our own health agency managers
which is currently at about, 1600 and we
would want to continue to see expansion
in that particular space so you will
obviously see a lot more expansion
initiatives being undertaken in the
context of retail health and therefore
to that extent that should logically
translate into an improved market share
uh in that particular segment while even
this year we would have loved to have
done better but honestly we have not
been able to completely leverage the uh
opportunity that one sees but given the
fact that we have been able to uh
strengthen our leadership team as well I
think one would expect a lot more to
happen in terms of expanding
distribution launching new products and
obviously strengthening the technology
deliverables uh so that's so agency will
continue to be a very very important
channel of sourcing and sanjie in the
last earning calls did speak about one
is one digital uh Channel and therefore
that will again continue to be a very
very important channel of sourcing and
if you look at just from the current
year standpoint the overall contribution
of the digital opportunity that spans
across I take care website Alliance
Partners etc etc that contribution has
been almost in the range of about 6 to
7% of the overall revenues and that's
again kind of compounding well in in
excess of almost about 20% year on year
so all in all I think uh it is going to
be a combination of all channels I think
there is going to be thrust of
investments in each of them if you ask
me which channel will by far gain the
Maximum Traction obviously retail health
is an area where we would want to kind
of significantly leverage faster and
then of course we have the digital
opportunity that one sees and then we
will continue to leverage on the other
channels of and more importantly I just
I did miss one of them which is the bank
Partnerships I think again that will be
a very very important area of sourcing
and within that icsi group will be a
very very important contribution for us
and hence we would obviously want to
leverage on each of these channels of
distribution thank you very much can I
can I just squeeze in one more can you
please uh share your outlook of the
health pricing both in the retail and
the group that would be helpful thank
you outlook on
health uh pricing pricing the health
insurance pricing yeah in both the
retail segment as well as in the group I
think uh it's it's it's a functional
loss ratio and as you said we will
continue to be a prudent underwriter in
both the segments uh most of the
industry including us have taken a hike
on the retail Health side uh last year
so we would believe as things stand we
would like to operate in this range uh
and while we will obviously keep
revisiting in terms of frequency as well
as a loss ratio that comes along with it
but uh that's what our view on retail
health is the group health is far more
Dynamic and driven by multiple you know
factors in the market uh is it holding
up overall years there at Le some bit of
a discipline that continues to exist and
if that's what stays then we would
obviously stay relevant if it does not
work out for us we would not hesitate to
move away and let go that business if
it's not making sense that charity we
have and we always m i again reiterate
that uh profit pools keep moving uh and
accordingly we have to be agile as an
organization we will take those calls uh
because we want to to the best of our
effort want to ensure that we deliver
what the market is expecting with us for
a multi-line multiproduct company like
us thank you very much thanks thank you
thank
you I would now like to hand the
conference over to Mr sanjie mantri for
closing comments over to you sir no
thank you so much for for joining in uh
it's an auspicious day of ram Navi and
probably some of you had holidays uh
it's always a pleasure uh interacting
with all of you the opportunity as it
stays the momentum that we have
developed we are excited about the
opportunity ahead uh look forward to
interacting with you in time to come and
all the best Take Care thank you so
much thank you on behalf of ICICI
Lombard General Insurance Company
Limited that concludes this confence
thank you all for joining us you may now
disconnect your lines